Sector From Here
Tsukimonogatari
Ononoki Yotsugi is a doll.
To put it differently, she isn't human.
Not a person. Not a living thing. She isn't ordinary.
That is Ononoki Yotsugi...
A tsukumo-gami that serves as a shikigami.
She looks like a cute little girl, eccentric in speech and actions.
Though she is an amusing and expressionless child, her true nature is that of an aberration.
A demon. A monster. She's that kind of being.
Bee
Bird
Monkey
Devil
Snake
Cat
Crab
Snail
Evil Spirits
Because of that, she doesn't fit in with human society well.
No. You know, that's not really the case, master.
In her case.
She was born from a human's corpse, she's a doll...
and she looks like a human. She pretends to be a human being.
Does that...
Does that mean that she's striving to be human, that she's doing her best to try and be human?
If so, I wonder...
But, according to Shinobu, that's not quite right.
Apparently the fact that she pretends to be human is proof that she isn't trying.
In The End, It Is Merely The Means To Blend Into Human Society.
It Is Only A Means To Become Compatible.
So Therefore Not A Means To Assimilate.
No matter how much you study a foreign language, and learn to speak it fluently...
It is just a means to communicate with those of another country.
It's not necessarily an effort to assimilate into the other culture.
It's the same thing.
She was created in the likeness of humans not to be a human being, nor to become a person.
It was to be together with humans.
Not to be, not to become.
But to be together.
To Create An Amicable Relation With Someone In Another Culture,
You Must Understand That Foreign Culture And Look Into It—
When In Rome, Do As The Romans Do
In the first place, you know master...
Why do aberrations in legends, or in other words so-called metamorphic monsters,
always take the shape of humans or animals?
Basically, they're unreal existences, yet they base their shape on things that really exist.
You've never really thought about it?
I Had Never Thought About It.
That Is Well, If I Can Say So,
Perhaps The Limitations Of Human Imagination—
I Had Never Thought About It.
That Is Well, If I Can Say So,
Perhaps The Limitations Of Human Imagination—
I Had Never Thought About It.
That Is Well, If I Can Say So,
Perhaps The Limitations Of Human Imagination—
I Had Never Thought About It.
That Is Well, If I Can Say So,
Perhaps The Limitations Of Human Imagination—
Humans Can Only Speak About Reality Using Words They Know—
That Is Well, If I Can Say So,
Perhaps The Limitations Of Human Imagination—
Humans Can Only Speak About Reality Using Words They Know—
That Is Well, If I Can Say So,
Perhaps The Limitations Of Human Imagination—
Humans Can Only Speak About Reality Using Words They Know—
In the end...
Abberations exist thanks to people... They exist because humans exist.
This doesn't mean that aberrations are dependent on humans though.
It just means that if there's nobody to observe, nobody's being observed.
Even I, who was dubbed a legendary vampire,
would not be a vampire without that legend. The same as any other aberration.
If you can't speak of the aberration,
it isn't an aberration.
A ghost story must be a story of the supernatural.
l
Well, This Is More That Unpleasant Guy In a Hawaiin Shirt's Values
and Way of Thinking
—
When you dig down, an aberration is just an attachment.
Attachment. Emotions.
Can that perhaps be a feeling similar to sympathizing with a doll?
For tsukumo-gami, and what people consider "what-a-waste ghosts,"
one could say they're all created like this.
The way of thinking that gods can reside in all things...
The belief that there is a myriad of gods... I hear that's something unique to Japan.
However, it doesn't matter if it's living or not...
sympathy for things other than humans exists all over the world.
That is why ghost stories are told all over the world.
They are told,
by humans. I can be convinced of that.
No, it's a story I have no choice but to be convinced of.
After the numerous aberrations, as someone who has told stories of aberrations...
About the vampire.
About the cat.
About the crab.
About the snail.
About the monkey.
About the snake.
About the bee.
About the phoenix.
As the one who told these stories,
I have no choice but to be convinced.
And now, I am once again trying to tell a story, one of a doll.
But I feel like I've talked too much.
Urban legends.
Street gossip.
Secondhand information.
When they're spoken too much, they lose their meaning.
The hair-raising and awe-inspiring feelings both disappear.
Thinking back to the "darkness" that started on the first day of the second term...
Or Sengoku Nadeko's incident with the snake god around the New Year...
I wonder how much longer things will go like this. I'm kinda fed up with it.
To The Apparitions Which I Meet One After Another
Feeling That Trickery Is Starting To No Longer Work
I Also Feel Despair From It—
But that feeling is a luxury.
To think that it will continue forever is a luxury.
This world doesn't work like that. I should have known that.
No, thinking of "what if" is no use this late.
Every story is marked with "The End" at some point.
What Is This? The Rowdy Days Seem To Continue For Just A Bit Longer?
The Repetition Of Such Words
Will Someday Reach Its Limit.
The story of the doll that I'm going to tell is the story where I came to understand that.
The story with the message that I understood, whether I liked it or not.
That is why this is the beginning of the end.
This story is about how a human named Araragi Koyomi...
about how myself, Araragi Koyomi...
will end and begin. That is this story.
Episode Tai (Body)
Yotsugi Doll Part One
Under the breathtaking twilight
doki doki no yuuyami ni
The sparkling stars flutter
kira kira na hoshi ga chirari
That might be enough
sore de ii no kamo
But I am sure there is a reason
kitto riyuu ga atte
We cannot be sure that the things we see
mieteiru koto ga
Are all that there is
subete to ha kagiranai
The reason behind your smile
kimi no egao no wake
Is the reason for my tears
boku ni ha namida no wake de
If I study it thoroughly
tsukitsumeteshimattara
I will not be able to keep moving forward
sono saki ni ha ne susumenai
I bestow my wishes upon that falling star
ano nagareboshi negai wo nosete
The future I have been working towards and everything else
mezashiteita mirai mo zenbu
I grow unable to understand it all
wakaranakunatteiku
In that way
bokutachi ha sonna fuu ni
We pass the day
kyou wo yarisugosu
Even though it is full of contradictions
mujun darake nandakedo
Goodnight, for tonight
konya ha oyasumi
The thrilling orange
doki doki no orenji to
And the sparkling mint flavour
kira kira no minto fureibaa
Under the breathtaking twilight
doki doki no yuuyami ni
The sparkling stars flutter
kira kira na hoshi ga chirari
Episode Tai (Body)
Yotsugi Doll Part One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Nii-chan! Damn you, it's morning!
You can't keep sleeping!
Today, I suddenly wanted to think about having or not having an alarm clock.
Bluntly, the words "alarm clock" and the existence of such a thing are not things I like.
Reference
Omitted
That this hatred may be linked to alarm clocks...
Alarm clock... Alarm clock...
Arm clock al...
Omitted
To the phrase that states "You awaken someone's eyes," I feel crazy anger, and because of that...
So, we who are woken up would like to say this to the alarm clock.
Not with hatred, but with thanks.
Thank you, and good night.
Don't sleep!
Just because you don't want to wake up, you're gonna use that big excuse Nii-chan?
In the first place, we're not alarms but your little sisters. We're alarm sisters.
Interesting. I'd like them to make figures out of you or something.
All right, I'm awake. My consciousness is fully aware.
February 13th, huh?
It's the day before Valentine's Day.
Hey, little sisters, are you ready to give me some chocolate?
Wow!
You know, Nii-chan, this isn't the time for you to be worried about Valentine's Day.
Not the time, nor the hour.
Come on, there's only a month left until you take those college entrance exams.
Get it?
If you don't get it, you understand that you're better off dead, right? I'll kill you!
Even if you say that, I don't remember being told that, and I have no clue why I'd be killed off.
Geez. Geez, I say.
This is why you're a piece of trash, Nii-chan.
Now, wake up and go study already. Cram yourself into that corner.
This may be the time for a last spurt, but I don't think this is the time for me to cram myself...
And you, if you let your guard down, you won't be able to go up a grade either.
It's not the time for you to worry just about me.
Fine, I'll tickle you.
Take that, take that.
That won't work! I've trained well, so the soles of my feet are pretty thick!
Got it, I'll lick it then.
Take that, take that.
I Will Especially Keep It A Secret
Whether I Actually Licked Or Karen Pulled Her Foot
Back Before I Licked To Preserve The Privacy Of Us Siblings.
I Will Especially Keep It A Secret
Whether I Actually Licked Or Karen Pulled Her Foot
Back Before I Licked To Preserve The Privacy Of Us Siblings.
SECRET
I Will Especially Keep It A Secret
Whether I Actually Licked Or Karen Pulled Her Foot
Back Before I Licked To Preserve The Privacy Of Us Siblings.
SECRET
I Will Especially Keep It A Secret
Whether I Actually Licked Or Karen Pulled Her Foot
Back Before I Licked To Preserve The Privacy Of Us Siblings.
SECRET
Whether I Actually Licked Or Karen Pulled Her Foot
Back Before I Licked To Preserve The Privacy Of Us Siblings.
I Will Especially Keep It A Secret
SECRET
Whether I Actually Licked Or Karen Pulled Her Foot
Back Before I Licked To Preserve The Privacy Of Us Siblings.
SECRET
I Will Especially Keep It A Secret
Whether I Actually Licked Or Karen Pulled Her Foot
Back Before I Licked To Preserve The Privacy Of Us Siblings.
SECRET
Looks like you're fine now.
Then I'm gonna go running for a bit.
I'm gonna go a run-ning.
So have the bath ready for me.
A bath so hot I'll get burned. If you'd like, how about coming to run with me for a while, Nii-chan?
There's no way I'd be able to keep up with the pace you set.
You always go running at the pace of a 100-meter dash.
And you run like, a full marathon. Like 42.195 kilometers!
Go run with Kanbaru or something!
See ya! Daddy-O-Nii-chan!
Now...
I guess I'll go get that bath ready for Karen's sake.
For Karen's sake, I can take the effort this early in the morning
to spare some time and whip up this old body to prepare her bath.
You're so condescending, Onii-chan.
You're forcing entire layers of condescendence.
She trains her body hard like a samurai sword.
But this sharp mind wonders, why doesn't she join an athletic club or something?
Karen-chan can't join any athletic clubs.
It's a rule of her school of karate. All students are forbidden from joining any clubs.
'Cause they're the type about execution. 'Cause they're totally the type about execution.
'Cause they're the type. 'Cause.
I don't really get it but...
Tsukihi, don't you think it's a waste to see Karen's talent buried away?
Meow?
Though she doesn't come close to me, she's a human that's really overflowing with talent.
Like, don't you want to see her in the spotlight or something?
Not just tied down to the school, or the Fire Sisters.
That's right, we can have her aim to be an Olympic ath- Ouch!
What was that about?!
Eh? You were being irritating, Onii-chan...
Seems Like She Doesn't Feel Any Doubt In Her Actions.
Anyone that tries to sever the bonds of the Fire Sisters can't be forgiven. Not even you, Onii-chan.
Eh? You were thinking about disbanding though.
You said you'd invite me to the disbanding party filled with junior high girls.
It pisses me off when someone else says it.
Well...
Even without having someone like you say it, Onii-chan,
it's true that Karen-chan will retire from the Fire Sisters someday for sure.
I'm sure lots of things will happen once she's in high school.
I think all sorts of things will dazzle her.
The environment will change too.
But even then, I don't think Karen-chan will quit going to that dojo.
Karen-chan is fascinated with her master right now.
Well, I don't know how my college entrance exam will go.
I don't know which way it will roll.
But, no matter which way it goes, in due time,
my environment will change more than Karen's for sure.
Before that, for Karen and Tsukihi...
My heart as the big brother tells me I need to instill some logic into them.
Surprisingly enough, a thought like that isn't missing from my brain.
Right. It's high time that the Fire Sisters wake up.
And me too.
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
I'll make it really hot, just how she likes it.
I want to take a bath now, too.
Onii-chan!
You're the west! No wait, you're the worst!
West!
The Worst
You said you were drawing a bath just for Karen, but you were planning on bathing first!
You're the worst!
The worst!
Look at you though...
Looking at the way you're dressed, I can't help but think you were about to do the same thing...
In any case, get out of my way Onii-chan.
I'm going to bathe in that bath.
If you get in my way, Onii-chan, even you will regret it.
Little sister...
If you insist on bathing right now, you'll need to bea- Ah!
That was dangerous!
What the hell are you doing?!
You just said, "Defeat your big brother."
If you want to pass here...
Okay, got it. Onii-chan, let's take this path.
This path?
This path to the bathroom to bathe together.
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Tsukimonogatari
One
From Here
Why...
Why Is This?
How Did It End Up Like This?
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Eh? You Don't Want To Go?
Then, Does Onii-chan's Steam Rise
In His Hot Spring At His Little Sister?
Impossible!
Impossible, We're In
In The Bathroom!
「
」
Hey You, Are You All Talk?
I Guess You're All Bark And No Bite.
You Didn't Have The Guts To
Take A Bath With Me In Reality,
Did You, You Chicken Girl!
」
「
Hey You, Are You All Talk?
I Guess You're All Bark And No Bite.
You Didn't Have The Guts To
Take A Bath With Me In Reality,
Did You, You Chicken Girl!
」
「
Hey You, Are You All Talk?
I Guess You're All Bark And No Bite.
You Didn't Have The Guts To
Take A Bath With Me In Reality,
Did You, You Chicken Girl!
」
「
Hey You, Are You All Talk?
I Guess You're All Bark And No Bite.
You Didn't Have The Guts To
Take A Bath With Me In Reality,
Did You, You Chicken Girl!
」
「
Hey You, Are You All Talk?
I Guess You're All Bark And No Bite.
You Didn't Have The Guts To
Take A Bath With Me In Reality,
Did You, You Chicken Girl!
」
「
Hey You, Are You All Talk?
I Guess You're All Bark And No Bite.
You Didn't Have The Guts To
Take A Bath With Me In Reality,
Did You, You Chicken Girl!
」
「
Hey You, Are You All Talk?
I Guess You're All Bark And No Bite.
You Didn't Have The Guts To
Take A Bath With Me In Reality,
Did You, You Chicken Girl!
」
「
Hey You, Are You All Talk?
I Guess You're All Bark And No Bite.
You Didn't Have The Guts To
Take A Bath With Me In Reality,
Did You, You Chicken Girl!
」
「
Hey You, Are You All Talk?
I Guess You're All Bark And No Bite.
You Didn't Have The Guts To
Take A Bath With Me In Reality,
Did You, You Chicken Girl!
」
「
Hey You, Are You All Talk?
I Guess You're All Bark And No Bite.
You Didn't Have The Guts To
Take A Bath With Me In Reality,
Did You, You Chicken Girl!
」
「
Hey You, Are You All Talk?
I Guess You're All Bark And No Bite.
You Didn't Have The Guts To
Take A Bath With Me In Reality,
Did You, You Chicken Girl!
」
「
I Guess You're All Bark And No Bite.
You Didn't Have The Guts To
Take A Bath With Me In Reality,
Hey You, Are You All Talk?
Did You, You Chicken Girl!
「
」
I Guess You're All Bark And No Bite.
You Didn't Have The Guts To
Take A Bath With Me In Reality,
Hey You, Are You All Talk?
Did You, You Chicken Girl!
「
It Is Not A Bath As Spacious As The Anime Version,
Or Rather It Is An Average Sized Bath For An Average Family,
Onii-chan...
What is it, little sister?
Please say something. It's more awkward than I thought it would be.
Oh... If it's awkward just leave, Tsukihi.
You really do act like the good girl, don't you.
If you were going to back off, you shouldn't have suggested it in the first place.
I can say that to you too, Onii-chan. This is the definition of "reaping what you sow."
I'm just saying, I feel awkward looking at this body of yours, Onii-chan.
I feel nothing from bathing with you. Nothing at all.
Or, could it be Onii-chan, that your hot spring's steam is rising from your naked sister's body?
This is the bathroom, so do you want to leave?
You gonna say that twice?
You really going to say that twice?
You're the one that's charmed by my body.
Really, you want to touch these abs, don't you?
I don't want to do that at all.
I don't want to touch that eight-pack at all.
You're counting. Don't count my abs. You're looking!
You're totally looking at your little sister's boobs too.
Not possible.
It's not like this is the first time I've seen them.
Isn't that strange?! For a big brother to have seen his little sister's boobs.
I know all of it, you know! I know everything about those lumps of meat you have on your chest!
Don't call them lumps of meat! Don't make a young girl's boobs sound like something you can barbecue!
Onii-chan, anyway...
Let's take turns washing our hair.
We both have way too much hair,
so it's inefficient to wash our hair side by side like this. It's not economical.
I don't think the economy has anything to do with washing your hair, but...
Sometimes She Says Things That Are Just Right.
Tsukihi, what are we going to do if we can't sit side by side though?
Taking turns... Just what kind of a position will we need to take?
In other words, we do this!
I'm going to wash your hair like this, Onii-chan!
But At The Same Time It Was Short For "Wow, I See" As Well. W-
This "W-" Was Short For "What?" To Use As An Expression Of Surprise,
Okay, I'll stand it up.
Amazing! You're Astro Onii-chan! You're Super Onii-chan now!
Don't make it sound like I'm a Super Saiyan.
I'll rinse it off now.
Squeak, squeak, squeak.
I'll go on and wash your body like this.
Onii-chan, Onii-chan!
What? You sound like you just came up with something.
I just thought of a one-liner. A really funny one.
What's with the way you brought it up though? I don't feel good about this...
Come on, come on, look over here, over here.
What is it?
The title: Metropolitan Ordinance.
Scary!
What are you doing?!
And what are you doing?!
Posing like this and raising my arms up together,
and then saying "Sky Tree!" might have been better huh?
For Karen To Do So—
But In That Case, It Might Be Better
Come on, I'll wash your body now, so you can look away.
Hmm... Tsukihi...
I don't know if you're wishing for something, but why don't you at least cut your bangs?
You know, if I don't cut my hair well,
my bangs go "prickle, prickle" in my eyes and it hurts.
No matter how much loving care I give to my hair, it hurts if it gets in my eyes.
I see.
I Don't Get It Too Well.
Speaking of bangs...
Nadeko-chan was released from the hospital.
I see... I'm glad.
Huh? Your reaction wasn't how I imagined it.
I expected you to literally dance in joy.
I see.
All I could say was "I see." I didn't have the right to say anything else.
But I'm glad she was released from the hospital.
Though, I can never show my face to Sengoku again.
But I can still say I'm glad.
Somehow, I can think like that.
Onii-chan...
What?
Ouch, ouch, ouch, ouch, ouch!
My (ouch) head (ouch)...
Are you trying to (ouch) use your hands (ouch) as a vise?! (ouch, ouch)
Oh, sorry, sorry. I put too much strength in them.
You know Onii-chan, though I think you probably don't want me to say this to you...
It's because you probably don't want me to say it that I'll say it.
You're putting a lot of weight on your shoulders, you know? Too much.
The thing with Nadeko-chan couldn't be helped, but you can't carry it on your shoulders!
She Says Such Obvious Things,
About How She Was Missing For The Past Few Months
But Especially Tsukihi, About Sengoku,
Is Not Something She Knows The Minute Details Of.
Go visit her sometime, okay?
Nadeko-chan has to rest at home for a while,
and it'll be impossible for you to visit once you're busy with your college entrance exam.
Now that Nadeko Sengoku has descended from the mountain and her "disappearance" has been solved—
Well of course, that's a good thing. A wonderful thing.
However, that good, wonderful thing has once again created...
an extremely unstable area in this town. Or so I've been told.
And without solving that issue, or at least doing something about it if it can't be solved,
trouble will keep on coming to this town.
I have to say, I feel regret at the thought of leaving this place, even if you leave my sisters out of the equation.
Even if everything doesn't turn out fine, I need to make sure there's a good balance.
Balance, huh?
That wasn't my role at first.
It's not your role at all.
You carry too much weight on your shoulders, Onii-chan.
It's not like you can solve anything and everything, Onii-chan.
You can toss stuff aside, leave stuff alone, and know your place in the world.
You can live within your means and leave some stuff for others. I don't think that's that bad, you know?
About Nadeko-chan...
About Karen-chan...
And about me.
You worry about us way too much.
Actually Onii-chan, how's your studying for the college entrance exam really going?
You think you can get ahead with one more month?
Somehow... I'll figure something out.
So That's What I Had To Answer.
Even If It Wasn't, I Had To Answer That Way.
Such A Sad Self-Hypnosis.
That's why I'm saying it's time for you to cram instead of carrying these things on your shoulders, Onii-chan.
This is good advice, Onii-chan.
Is this really the time for you to be washing your little sister's body?
Well, it's not like I felt responsible
and assigned myself a particular role of washing you while you took your bath.
It's not that I'm lathering you up or fondling you.
In the first place, this hasn't solved the fundamental problem at all.
By going in order when washing ourselves, we solved the problem of how cramped the washing space was.
But, the first objective, about how narrow the tub is...
Yeah, that's right...
For the idea of bathing together, bathing with a young girl would have been better,
but the size of this tub makes it hard to do it with someone in junior high.
A young girl?
Nothing. Forget!
Do it again!
Do it again! Do it again!
Hey, do it again! Again, again!
The mirror was showing Tsukihi's naked body...
That was a natural phenomenon, and therefore something very natural.
However, there was something unnatural as well.
No. There was something supernatural.
Araragi Koyomi, or me, was not present in the mirror's image.
The mirror wasn't showing me.
As if I were an immortal aberration... A vampire.
These normal, ordinary days...
itsumo doori no atarimae no hibi wo
I wonder how long we can continue passing our time like this
itsumade konna fuu ni sugoserundarou
From the moment I thought about that
sonna koto kangaeta shunkan kara
I wondered if the end had already begun
owari ha hajimarikakechatteru no kana
Let’s blame it on my spot-on fortunes
yoku ataru uranai toka
Or on my curled up hair
haneta kami no sei ni shite
But I’m frozen in place again today, unable to change
dakedo kyou mo kawarenai mama tachisukumu
This is starting to become a world where you don't exist
kimi no inai sonna sekai ni natte hajimete
I don’t want to grow to regret the day called “today”
kyou to iu hi wo koukai suru nante iya da
There’s nothing but right now, and even though
ima shika nai itsudatte
I’ve always known that, I wasn’t able to say anything today
shitteta noni kyou mo ienakute
Even if we can never go back to those days
anna hibi ni mou nido to modorenai toshitemo
Listen, I want to start things from the beginning, over and over again
nee nando demo atarashiku hajimetai
There’s nothing but right now
ima shika nai itsudatte
Even though I’ve always known that, I want to tell you today
shitteru kara kyou ha iitakute